<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2021 on Layer9</title>
    <link>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/updates/2021/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2021 on Layer9</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy;{year}, All Rights Reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/updates/2021/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
      
      <item>
        <title>S6-init on Obarun</title>
        <link>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/unixlike/meme/arch_manjaro/2021-12-02_obarun-install/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/unixlike/meme/arch_manjaro/2021-12-02_obarun-install/</guid>
        <description>Obarun and S6 The suite S6 - Skarnet.org&amp;rsquo;s Small &amp;amp; Secure Supervision Software Suite includes an init, one of several projects that rebelled against SystemD by trying to prove there were better and/or simpler ways to do the same thing. For whom?
Despite the official implementation of S6 began to be on Alpine Linux, for some reason the author now collaborates with Adélie Linux, which I&amp;rsquo;ve already tried.
However, the most mature implementation of S6-init seems to be on Obarun, an Arch-based distro and, as far as I know, without any input from the author of S6, despite all of them being French.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>PKI OpenSSL (pt 1)</title>
        <link>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/sec/pki/opensslpki_1/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 01:13:41 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/sec/pki/opensslpki_1/</guid>
        <description>OpenSSL-based PKI (part 1) Sources:
https://openssl-ca.readthedocs.io/en/latest/index.html
https://www.golinuxcloud.com/tutorial-pki-certificates-authority-ocsp/
https://social.technet.microsoft.com/wiki/contents/articles/2900.offline-root-certification-authority-ca.aspx
https://pki-tutorial.readthedocs.io/en/latest/index.html
An airgapped Root CA The system that contains the RootCA is supposed to be airgapped, to be under controlled access, and to be used only for the emission of new CAs and revocation of compromised CAs. In this example, we can put everything on the same server, but one should try to separate the RootCA from the other CAs as much as possible.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Cisco and Huawei simulated routers</title>
        <link>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/networking/simul/gns3-ensp/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 03:10:41 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/networking/simul/gns3-ensp/</guid>
        <description>Some time ago, I needed to simulate a heterogeneous network, with a Cisco router connected to another Huawei router.
It wasn&amp;rsquo;t easy because IOS is not publicly available and the Huawei simulator, eNSP, is discontinued and only works on VirtualBox 5.
To make this simulation, a CPU that supports VM nesting (Second-Level Address Translation - SLAT) is required.
Simulation VM Create a Windows 7-based VM, with 4GB of RAM, 2 vCPUS and 4 network interfaces.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>PKI OpenSSL (pt 2)</title>
        <link>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/sec/pki/opensslpki_2/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 18:19:10 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/sec/pki/opensslpki_2/</guid>
        <description>OpenSSL PKI (part 2) - IntermediateCA Creating an IntermediateCA Once again, the intermediateCA(s) must be hosted in a separate system (server) from that which hosts the RootCA, and the RootCA&amp;rsquo;s system (root) should be airgapped and offline. In the online system I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s a bad idea to keep the secondary CAs under /root/ca, which allows the placing the RootCA&amp;rsquo;s certificate on the same path (/root/ca/certs/ca.cert.pem). However, this is the only information from the RootCA that needs to be brought to the online world where the secondary CAs reside; it is even debatable if it is worth bringing the RootCA&amp;rsquo;s CRL in PEM format and putting it in /root/ca/crl/ca.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>BIND9: from the start</title>
        <link>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/networking/protocols/2021-10-30_dns-bind9-tinycorelinux/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/networking/protocols/2021-10-30_dns-bind9-tinycorelinux/</guid>
        <description>BIND9 Installation The system where this BIND9 service was installed is the same described in the article TinyCoreLinux Installation.
There is a BIND9 package for TinyCore, but jusk like almost everything else, the installation is very do-it-yourself1. We&amp;rsquo;re not provided with a firelighter, and not even matches; we really have to scratch a couple of sticks next to some kindling to get some fire.
The BIND9 extension can be installed from the browser tce-ab or directly by the installer tce-load</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Computer Says No</title>
        <link>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/blog/2021-11-17_computersaysno/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/blog/2021-11-17_computersaysno/</guid>
        <description>I was just trying to downlood the ESXi evaluation&amp;hellip;
Unless this goes away tomorrow, it looks like my Type1 hypervisor journey will start with XCP-ng&amp;hellip;
You only get one chance to make a good impression.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>One Thousand Monkeys</title>
        <link>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/blog/2021-11-15_monkeys/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/blog/2021-11-15_monkeys/</guid>
        <description>I dun it!
The button to copy the contents of the code boxes now appears both in those that have syntax (highlight, chroma) as in those that don&amp;rsquo;t have:
1  cowsay &amp;#34;monkeys, I tell you!&amp;#34;   # output______________________&amp;lt; monkeys, I tell you! &amp;gt;----------------------\ ^__^\ (oo)\_______(__)\ )\/\||----w ||| ||How have I dun it? Dunno&amp;hellip;
Hence the title: one thousand monkeys banging on one thousand typewriters could write &amp;ldquo;The C Programming Language&amp;rdquo; if they had until the heat death of the Universe to do it.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>TinyCore Linux - Initial steps</title>
        <link>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/unixlike/meme/2021-10-29_tinycorelinux-install/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/unixlike/meme/2021-10-29_tinycorelinux-install/</guid>
        <description>For this system, which will eventually be a server called verynice, I made a VM with 256MB of RAM and 640MB of disk.
[TinyCore]1 is a very special Linux installation, destined for systems with very few resources. I&amp;rsquo;ll use the Deluxe version, CorePlus, with leather seats, GUI and possibility of disk installation, but there are leaner flavors of CoreLinux that will cheerfully boot from a 128MB flashdrive and load themselves to a RAMdrive at startup.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Copy button, take 1</title>
        <link>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/blog/2021-11-08_copy-button-1/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/blog/2021-11-08_copy-button-1/</guid>
        <description>The first time I tried to set up a Copy button for code boxes, I left an issue on Zdoc&amp;rsquo;s GitHub.
Some days ago, another Zdoc user published the solution that worked for him, and stimulated by that, I tried again.
Unfortunately, I must have manipulated my theme&amp;rsquo;s DOM code too much (tracking upstream is going to be impossible until I nuke it and pave it on the next Zdoc release) to be able to use his code, but I tried fiddling a little more with the code I had tried to use previously, which was based on this proposal by Tom Spencer.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Update about VyOS</title>
        <link>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/blog/2021-10-31_vyos2/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/blog/2021-10-31_vyos2/</guid>
        <description>As I said in a previous article, I was trying to check on VyOS, which seems to be a cheap way for testing network concepts without having to pay for Cisco Modeling Labs (the only legal way of using Cisco virtual systems) or something similar.
And I hit smack-dab into the issue of the Portuguese keyboard layout: there isn&amp;rsquo;t one. Yes, an SSH connection assumes the client&amp;rsquo;s layout - but you need to setup the network beforehand.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Adelie Linux - LiveCD Installation</title>
        <link>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/unixlike/musl/2021-09-13_adelie_livecd/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 23:07:43 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/unixlike/musl/2021-09-13_adelie_livecd/</guid>
        <description>LiveCD 1.0-RC2, MATE edition Development of the Adélie distro seemed to have stopped for a long time because the team dedicated themselves to the development of a graphical and scriptable setup program, called Horizon, and that took many resources off the development of the base system. There was much going on behind the scenes but from the outside all we could see was no new releases.
However, a recent reorganization put wind in their sails and the site has been much improved, looking sharp, professional and organized, the mailing-lists make more sense, and progress seems to be accelerating.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>PKI OpenSSL (pt 3)</title>
        <link>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/sec/pki/opensslpki_3/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 21:06:37 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/sec/pki/opensslpki_3/</guid>
        <description>Client and Server Certificates Now that we have our IntermediateCA properly configured, we can start using it to issue certificates.
Notes:
 You should use no less than half the bits used on the CA for keys The server&amp;rsquo;s CN should be its FQDN A server certificate needs to have the same FQDN repeated on the SAN information The client certificate&amp;rsquo;s CN can be anything, it&amp;rsquo;s not important. Certificates must be signed by the IntermediateCA Certificates usually last a year (365 days) and the maximum, since July 2019, is 824 days (+1) OpenSSL command for server certificate: -extensions server_cert OpenSSL command for client certificate: -extensions usr_cert Only if copy_extensions = copy or = all is on the [ca_default] section of intermediate/openssl.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Manifesto</title>
        <link>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/blog/2021-10-08_wat-do/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/blog/2021-10-08_wat-do/</guid>
        <description>Nutritional facts Don&amp;rsquo;t expect this site to have the usual content; I&amp;rsquo;ll hardly write the n-th article about installing Postfix or Arch Linux, configure a NextCloud instance or a VPN: not interesting, already done, adds no value. I&amp;rsquo;ll only do these kinds of thing if I stumble on HOWTOs so bad that&amp;rsquo;ll make me wonder if I&amp;rsquo;d do it a lot better.
Right now I&amp;rsquo;m interested in exploring the MUSL world, Some very specific Linux distros, and the S6 init; I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be shocked by the current state of the documentation and development of these systems, compared to the 50,000 articles on how to install Ubuntu (ballpark figures), but I am.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Musl</title>
        <link>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/unixlike/musl/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 23:09:50 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/unixlike/musl/</guid>
        <description>The musl C library is an alternative to the equivalent GNU library (glibc) and is used by some (but few) distributions, which are generally simpler, bespoke, light in resources and with much, much less polish than GNU/Linux distributions .
Which begs the question, of course, of what to call these distributions: musl/Linux? Although many of those use busybox as the base of the userland, others use GNU coreutils, so there&amp;rsquo;s some GNU in there as well.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Getch&#39;or VyOS heaaar!!!</title>
        <link>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/blog/2021-10-07_getchorvyoshear/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/blog/2021-10-07_getchorvyoshear/</guid>
        <description>Like many other Free and Open Source Software projects, Vyos decided that it was going to continue to be free as in freedom but would stop being for free. To convince enterprise users to pay up and contribute to the project with monies, they decided that binaries compiled and distributed for installation as an ISO image would only be available to the public in unstable versions, meaning, nightly builds. The last pre-compiled stable version available is 1.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Article Workflow</title>
        <link>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/blog/2021-09-22_workflow/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 00:54:14 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/blog/2021-09-22_workflow/</guid>
        <description>The workflow I use to make these articles is a jury-rigged hairball of a hack (did you expect anything else?)
I start by writing in Microsoft Word, because I&amp;rsquo;m used to it and I have some content in Word format that I want to bring to the site.
Then I convert the DOCX to MarkDown with Pandoc
pandoc -f docx -t gfm --wrap=none --extract-media images\&amp;lt;section&amp;gt;\&amp;lt;article&amp;gt; -o article.md .\article.docxThe advantages of using Pandoc are many:</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Article comments</title>
        <link>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/blog/2021-09-15_site-comments/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 14:19:12 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/blog/2021-09-15_site-comments/</guid>
        <description>At first I did not intend to enable comments, but since humans are social animals, I went to see if I could set up a system without having to hack too much.
At first I considered Disq.us, which comes with Hugo, but it has many issues.
Zdoc has Utteranc.es pre-configured, and it has the advantages of being limited to GitHub users (all good people) and to be statically stored on a repo.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Updates section</title>
        <link>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/blog/2021-09-04_updates-page/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 11:34:41 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/blog/2021-09-04_updates-page/</guid>
        <description>Zdoc has an &amp;ldquo;Updates&amp;rdquo; section, but the articles inside it were created by hand. Since I&amp;rsquo;m lazy (laziest person in the world right here) and I don&amp;rsquo;t like to do things by hand when they can be automated, I tried to get some way of producing a Site Index without handcrafting each page.
In WordPress and other dynamic platforms it&amp;rsquo;s dead easy, but on a static site like Hugo, all the proposed solutions involved plugins, NPM, Node.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Achievement unlocked: Lightbox</title>
        <link>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/blog/2021-09-02_lightbox/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 23:24:10 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/blog/2021-09-02_lightbox/</guid>
        <description>One thing that I don&amp;rsquo;t like about Zdoc is all the space taken by the sidebars, leaving little space on the center for the articles and leaving the images quite small (especially when they are widescreen screenshots).
I don&amp;rsquo;t understand enough HTML to try to widen the central column (apart from the built-in arrow on top that widens the content column but hides the TOC), but I can try to make the images be shown larger when you click on them.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>August 2021 Update</title>
        <link>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/blog/2021-08-28_site-update/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 19:08:10 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/blog/2021-08-28_site-update/</guid>
        <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been messing about some things behind the curtains:
Theme changes I wanted to use a Hugo theme for documentation (structured documents), if possible with an associated blog for less structured content.
My wishlist was (in no particular order):
 Light / dark theme Multilanguage (i18n) Several independent sections Ability to include in the code boxes not only line numbers but also prompts outside of the text, so that they were ignored when copying the contents of the box Have command output boxes with distinct formatting  I only found this theme, Zdoc, that had most of it (Docz seems to be shaping up as an alternative), but it still lacks a lot:</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Dotfiles</title>
        <link>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/unixlike/dotfiles/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 14:25:08 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/unixlike/dotfiles/</guid>
        <description>Linux Dotfiles I&amp;rsquo;ve been gathering settings that make my life easier by solving little nagging problems and papercuts.
Publishing those files here allows me to download them wherever I create a new user account.
The URL for downloading will be https://tiagojsilva.github.io/unix/dotfiles/file
There&amp;rsquo;s a TAR archive of all the files, which you can install right in your home folder (~) with:
1  wget -O- https://tiagojsilva.github.io/unix/dotfiles/dotfiles.tar | tar -xvf- -C ~   .</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Hello World</title>
        <link>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/blog/2021-08-09_hello-world/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 22:16:15 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/blog/2021-08-09_hello-world/</guid>
        <description>Sit down and take a load off.
I have been fortunate to make professions of my passions; as a young&amp;rsquo;un, I had to choose one of them (Sound for Picture), but the swings and roundabouts of life led me to embrace another one, which is IT. By the end of it I ended up back where I had started, but I don&amp;rsquo;t consider it wasted time; I had wonderful teachers and colleagues, and learned a lot of stuff that I had always wanted to know.</description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>