<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2022 on Layer9</title>
    <link>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/updates/2022/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2022 on Layer9</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy;{year}, All Rights Reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/updates/2022/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Windows Pro Wrestling</title>
        <link>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/microsoft/win11/2022-02-20_pro-wrestling/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/microsoft/win11/2022-02-20_pro-wrestling/</guid>
        <description>On February 16th 2022, Microsoft announced the first big evolution for Windows 11, with Dev Build 22557; the list of changes was long, and juicy, but what gave everyone a chill down the spine was this:
 Similar to Windows 11 Home edition, Windows 11 Pro edition now requires internet connectivity during the initial device setup (OOBE) only. If you choose to setup device for personal use, MSA will be required for setup as well.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Microsoft CLI Editors</title>
        <link>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/microsoft/tools/2022-01-15_cli-editors/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/microsoft/tools/2022-01-15_cli-editors/</guid>
        <description>Wanted, Dead or Alive: CLI Editor This article was inspired by the page Wanted: Console Text Editor for Windows, which is very thorough and I strongly recommend that you read it (while you&amp;rsquo;re at it, put a star in the Github profile of the author, Antoni Sawicki); however, I discovered so many things in the meantime that I decided maybe I can give my two cents about this.
The original article begins with what are also my reasons to investigate this issue:</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Massive Search and Replace with Notepad&#43;&#43;</title>
        <link>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/blog/2022-01-27_multiple-search-and-replace/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/blog/2022-01-27_multiple-search-and-replace/</guid>
        <description>In my article workflow I keep having to convert tags into Hugo shortcodes, and removing the escapes on all the characters Pandoc thinks it has to protect.
Doing this one by one is the type of work which has me running for some kind of automation - and that&amp;rsquo;s why I say I&amp;rsquo;m the laziest man in the world.
I tried to get some kind of plugin for Notepad++ or VSCode that would help me, but in the end they all had problems; namely, since my targets and my substitutions have many special characters, I wanted to avoid tools that used regular expressions.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Escape From CentOS</title>
        <link>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/unixlike/rpm/redhat/rocky_almalinux/2022-01-10_escape-from-centos/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://tiagojsilva.github.io/en/unixlike/rpm/redhat/rocky_almalinux/2022-01-10_escape-from-centos/</guid>
        <description>How we got here The Centos distribution has always been a strange beast: how could it be that the main exclusively paid Linux distribution (Red Hat Enterprise Linux, or RHEL) had a totally free clone?
Therefore, and for reasons I will elaborate below, it did not surprise me that the conditions of use for CentOS have changed, although the method, the time and the way everything was communicated will be a case-study on how-not-to-do&amp;hellip;</description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>